Muhammad Fathir Irhas

Jakarta - Tangerang

□ (+62) 812-2444-1284 | 🗷 fathir.irhas@outlook.com | 🏕 mfathirirhas.github.io | 🖫 mfathirirhas | 🛅 mfathirirhas

Summary_

Highly passionate and enthusiast Software Engineer mostly in backend development and little frontend stuffs. Always learning to improve skills and willing to share. Able to work independently and in team. Write good and testable code and refactor them if needed. Provide solutions and improvement if needed. Have experiences developing system and services.

Education

Telkom University Bandung, Indonesia

SARJANA KOMPUTER(S.KOM)

GPA: 3.34

Experience_

Tokopedia Jakarta, Indonesia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jul 2018 - Now

- Use Golang, Javascript, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, NSQ, gRPC, and GQL.
- Contribute in Saldo Tokopedia, Internal Tools, and some investment products.
- Contribute in Saldo Tokopedia Saldo Penghasilan separation.
- Revamp Saldo Tokopedia legacy front end.
- · Rewrite Saldo Tokopedia legacy codebase to implement interface based development and creating testable code.
- · Implement unit tests.
- Develop services doing CRUD in PostgreSQL and MySQL as persistence and Redis as cache.
- Develop APIs in REST, gRPC, and GQL.
- · Develop message queue using NSQ.
- · Develop cron for task scheduling.
- · Create EGold(Tokopedia Emas) metrics monitoring in datadog.
- Monitor services from datadog, prometheus, and server log.
- · Collaborate with other team to provide interface and integration to/from Fintech's products/services.
- Migrate some legacy internal API from Perl to Golang.
- Execute tickets coming from users through ops team relating to issues in products.

Anabatic Technologies

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

Nov 2016 - Dec 2017

2012 - 2016

- **TECHNICAL CONSULTANT**
- · Monitor client's app running
- · Support product development and customization

Emporia Digital Raya, Anabatic Technologies

• Work in Agile running sprint every 2 weeks.

- SOFTWARE ENGINEER(JUNIOR) · Maintain Main site.
- Develop UI components using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and JSP.
- · Develop web services in form of REST APIs, firebase push notif, mail services, authentication for mobile apps using PHP, Java and MySQL.
- · Versioning and deployment.

Chevron Pacific Indonesia Duri Riau, Indonesia

INTERNSHIP 2015

- Internship under UTC-POD Team in IT Departement.
- Create simple web app using C# ASP.Net to handle request for well surveys.

Skill

GOLANG, JS, POSTGRE, MYSQL, REDIS, NSQ, API, REST, GRPC, GQL, TEST

C#, Python, Java, PHP(Laravel & Codeigniter), Wordpress, Excel



Informatics Lab, Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

2013 - 2015

PRACTICUM ASSISTANT

• Held and support main practicum

Software Engineering Lab, Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

LAB ASSISTANT

2015 - 2016 • Study and research group. Held and support some lab activities including tutoring, mentoring, sharing knowledge, workshop, movies, game,

Hackathon MDK 2.0 Bandung, Indonesia

CONTESTANT Oct 2015

• Participate in second Hackathon held by Telkom around Indonesia.

game development community indie game developer enthusiast and other activities.

• Developed simple web services to be consumed by Android

Other_

Blog: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/blog More: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/resume Portfolio: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/portfolio